原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     tong大梨  屯栗子  海云生
翻译     星星与弹幕狗  Carolingo
翻译     吃冰棒  glida  布塔
校对     布塔诚荐
时间轴   知之  caroline
时间轴   没有影子  紫夏  西·查
鸣谢     天之行者
后期     渔夫
总监     布塔
你好  这里是
Hello, you have reached...
阿尔多尔家
the Ardor residence.
请在滴声后留言
Please leave a message after the tone.
妈  爸  我是丹妮
Hey, Mom, hey, Dad, it's Dani.
抱歉这么晚打给你们
I'm sorry to be calling so late.
我就是问问家里情况
I'm just checking in.
看看是不是一切都好
Making sure everything's okay.
泰莉给我发了封很吓人的邮件
Listen, I got kind of a scary email from Terri
之后她就不回复我了
and she hasn't been responding.
老一套了
Surprise, surprise.
但是  听起来好像
But, yeah, it sounds like you guys
你们吵架了还是出什么事了
have been fighting or something happened.
总之  我就是有点担心
Anyway, uh, I just got a little worried.
有空的时候给我回个电话吧
So, if you can call when you can,
当然了  你们知道我一直都在
and of course, you know I'm... I'm always here
有需要就告诉我
if you need anything,
我随时都在
of course.
就这样  我爱你们  再见
Okay, um, I love you. All right, bye.
亲爱的丹妮
我受不了了  一切都是黑暗的  爸妈也一起走  再见
丹妮·阿尔多尔
这是什么意思
泰莉
你为什么给我发了这种东西又不回我了  至少接个电话啊
泰莉·阿尔多尔
亲爱的丹妮
我受不了了  一切都是黑暗的  爸妈也一起走  再见
丹妮·阿尔多尔
这是什么意思
也一起走  再见
克里斯蒂安
-喂  -喂  亲爱的
- Hey. - Hey, sweetie.
你在干什么
What are you up to?
和马克抽了点大麻脂
Just smoked some resin with Mark
现在我们订了披萨
and now we're getting pizza.
不错
Nice.
丹妮  丹妮
Hi, Dani. Hi, Dani.
他在跟你打招呼  一遍一遍不停地说
He's saying "hi" right now, over and over.
-你好  马克  -你好  马克
- Hi, Mark. - Hi, Mark.
我打电话是想问问
So, I was calling just to see if you...
你一会还想不想一起玩
You still wanted to hang out later?
我们有说过今晚有安排吗
Did we talk about doing something tonight?
没有...没具体定下来
I mean, not... Not concretely,
但是  我就是想问问
but, I just wanted to see...
那...好啊
Well... Okay.
好  我应该能过去
Yeah, I should be able to swing by.
-好  -那好
- Cool. - Yeah, okay.
你妹妹的事怎么样了
How's the sister situation?
这个
Well...yeah
我给她发了三封邮件
I emailed her three times and
还是没有回复
still no response
所以我现在有点担心
so I'm getting a little bit nervous, so...
肯定没事的
I'm sure it's fine.
嗯  大概没事
Yeah, probably...
这对她来说是家常便饭了  丹妮
She does this every other day, Dani.
就是因为你总是纵容她
And only because you let her.
我不是纵容她  她有双相障碍  所以...
Well, I don't let her, she's bipolar, so...
我知道  但是你的确挺纵容她的  宝贝
Yeah, I know. But, you do though, babes.
你直接跳到危机模式
You go straight to crisis mode.
这  她是我妹妹
Well, she's my sister
你也说了这封邮件看起来不太寻常
and even you said that this email seemed different.
对  但是
Yeah, right, but...
真的不寻常吗
Is it though, really?
很明显又是吸引注意力的小伎俩
It's still just another obvious ploy for attention
和之前害你惊恐发作的伎俩如出一辙
just like every other panic attack she's given you.
对  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
你说得对  我知道
You are right, yeah, I know.
你做出的回应越多
I mean, the more you respond
她就会越受到鼓励
the more she's encouraged to keep...
我知道我知道  你说得对  你说得对
No, I know, I know, I know. You're right, you're right.
我就是  我就是不长记性  谢谢你
I just... I just needed to be reminded, thank you.
有你我真幸运
I'm very lucky to have you.
这个嘛
Yeah, well.
我爱你
I love you.
好了  晚点见
Okay, I'll see you later?
-行  -好
- Yeah. - Okay.
-再见  马克  -再见  马克
- Bye, Mark. - Bye, Mark.
行了  我爱你
Okay, I love you.
-好  -再见
- All right. - Bye.
他的语气  听他说话的声音就能听出来
It's in his tone, like, you can hear it in his voice,
他是鼓起勇气有话要说
he's just working up the nerve to say something.
那就直接点  跟他挑明
So be direct! Confront him.
但万一是我吓到他了呢
What if I've scared him, though?
我总是把他卷进我们家这点破事里
I'm always roping him into my family crap.
什么叫把他卷进去了
How do you rope him in?
我一直都在依赖他
I'm always leaning on him!
我今天甚至哭着打给他
Like, I even called him today in tears
因为我妹妹又写了一封吓人的邮件
because my sister wrote another stupid scary email.
这就是男友的用处啊
That's what he's there for.
万一我把他吓跑了怎么办
What if I'm scaring him off?
你妹妹写什么了
What did your sister write?
就是一些不吉利的废话
Just some ominous bullshit
劳拉西泮
[可用于治疗焦虑]
和之前一个德行  太折磨人了
like she always does and it's torture.
我一直依赖他来支持我
And I lean on him constantly for support.
万一我给他的压力太大了怎么办
Like, what if I have overwhelmed him
让他认为我包袱太多了
and he thinks that I just have too much baggage?
如果真是这样的话  那正好摆脱他  对吧
Well, if that's the case, then good riddance, right?
不  不能因为...我太过分了
No, not if I... I went too far,
我对他太依赖了
if I leaned too much.
你没有  你需要他的时候他就该支持你
You didn't! He should be there when you need him.
但是如果我总是需要他
Yeah, but what if I need him too often
这就变成负担了呢
and it becomes a chore?
那说明他不是对的人
Then he's not the right guy.
我担心死了  求你回邮件
因为这永远都不该是负担
Because it shouldn't ever be a chore.
如果他依赖你  你会觉得是负担吗
Would it be a chore if he leaned on you?
但是他对我一点索求都没有
Yeah, but he doesn't ask me for anything.
我都没见他哭过
I've never even seen him cry,
丹妮·阿尔多尔
泰莉
你为什么给我发了这种东西又不回我了  至少接个电话啊
求你回邮件  泰莉
你不能给我发了这种邮件之后又玩消失
我担心死了  求你回邮件
所以总是我在依赖他
so I'm the only one that's leaning.
或是说只有你敞开心扉了
Or the only one opening up.
只有你让自己露出脆弱的一面
The only one making yourself vulnerable.
未知来电
这才是亲密
That's intimacy.
老兄
Dude.
你不能再犹豫下去了
You have gotta get off the fence with this.
要是我之后又后悔了
What if I regret it later
却没办法挽回她了呢
and I can't get her back?
-你肯定不会想挽回她  -没准呢
- You don't want her back! - But I might.
好吧  那你可以
Okay, well, then you can
尽情跟我们抱怨你有多后悔
bitch to us about how much you regret it for that day
然后我们再一次提醒你
and then we'll remind you again
你一直都想摆脱这段糟心的关系
that you've been wanting out of this stupid relationship
大概有  一年了
for, like, a year now
然后你就可以找个真的喜欢做爱的小妞
and then you can find a chick who actually likes sex
还不会每天都给你找一堆麻烦
and doesn't drag you through a million hoops every day.
你觉得你内心有没有受虐倾向
Do you think there is a masochistic part of you
你上演这出闹剧是为了
that is playing out this particular drama
回避你真正需要完成的工作
to avoid the work you actually need to be doing?
我有什么工作需要完成  乔希
What work do I need to be doing, Josh, exactly?
我也说不好  没准该写开题报告了
Well, I dunno, your prospectus, maybe?
你的博士论文
Your PhD...
行  谢谢你给我做心理分析
Okay, thanks for the psychoanalysis.
跟学术无关  乔希
It's not about academics, Josh.
我就是想让你专注点
I'm just trying to get you focused.
-要找零吗  -给你的小费
- Change? - That's for you.
看见没  你现在就能去把那姑娘的肚子搞大
See? You could be getting that girl pregnant right now.
而且别忘了那些瑞典女人
And don't forget about all the Swedish women
你可以在六月让她们怀孕
you can impregnate in June.
-行了  -别忘了
- Okay, guys. - Don't forget about
那些瑞典挤奶女工
all the Swedish milkmaids.
丹妮
不会又是她吧
That's not her again.
不是吧
Seriously?
我的天
Oh, my God.
-她需要看心理医生了  -她有心理医生
- She needs a therapist, dude. - She has a therapist.
那她就应该打给心理医生而不是你
So then she should call her therapist and not you.
这简直就是虐待
It's literally abuse.
-她在虐待你  -借过
- She's abusing you. - 'Scuse me.
-不行  -天呐
- Nope. - My God.
行了  让我过去
Okay, excuse me, guys.
真好
Great.
-喂  -不
- Hey. - No.
-丹妮  宝贝  -不不不
- Dani, babe? - No, no, no.
丹妮·阿尔多尔发来四条新消息
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no!
仲夏夜惊魂
宝贝
Hey, babe.
感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
我起来了
I'm up.
你要去哪
Where you going?
我准备去参加派对  就去45分钟
I was just gonna go to that party for 45 minutes.
不过你接着睡吧
But, you just keep sleeping.
不
No.
不  我和你一起去
No, I'll come with you.
你确定睡够了吗
You sure you got enough sleep?
反正也睡不着
I wasn't sleeping anyway.
我真他妈的害怕过夏天
Yeah, I'm fucking dreading the summer.
闷在那个狗窝里
Stuck in a shit-ass hole
每天听着我爸干我后妈
listening to my step-mom fuck my dad all day.
我愿意听你爸干你后妈
I'll listen to your step-mom fuck your dad.
乔希  你要去欧洲了吗
Hey, Josh, you, going to Europe?
对  对  为了写论文
Yeah, yeah, for my thesis,
你知道  我们都要去
you know, we all are.
你们都要去
You're all going?
对  他们都要去拜访我在哈尔辛兰的家
Yeah, they're all coming to visit my home in Halsingland.
在瑞典
Sweden.
是去办事吗  还是去玩
Any occasion, or is it just for fun?
我要做调研
Well, I'm... I'm doing my research
这几个就是跟我一起去
these guys are just tagging along.
佩尔先生邀请我们
Mr. Pelle's invited us to
去他的约德尔农场的参加地道的嬉皮仲夏节
an authentic hippie midsummer at his yodeling farm.
是吗
Yeah?
我们商量过这事
I mean, we were talking about it.
我们考虑了一下
We were thinking about it.
什么时候去
For when?
六月中旬到七月中旬
Mid-June to mid-July.
对  两周之后
Yeah, two weeks from now?
对
Yeah.
前提是我们真的要去
I mean, that's if we even go.
我可能不去  不过
I'm probably not gonna go, but...
对  我们商量过
Yeah, we were talking about it.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Fine.
就是感觉太诡异了
That was just really weird.
什么诡异
What was?
就是
The...
去瑞典
Sweden.
我都不知道
I had no idea.
你什么意思
Well, what do you mean?
我跟你说过我想去
'Cause I told you I wanted to go.
好吧  但我不知道你真的要去
Okay, fine, but I didn't know you were going.
我今天才决定的
I just decided today.
我没有瞒着你
I wasn't keeping it from you.
你都准备好机票了
You already have a ticket.
对不起
I'm sorry?
好吧  你就
Okay, well, just,
想象如果你在一个派对上  有人问
imagine if you were at a party and someone said,
"暑假你有什么安排吗"
"Hey, what're you doing for summer?"
然后我的朋友说
And then my friend said,
"我们要去中国玩三个月"
"We're going to China for three months
"两周内就要启程了"
and we're leaving in two weeks..."
是瑞典  只去一个半月
It's Sweden, for a month and a half.
而且这是你第一次听说
And it was the first you'd ever heard of it.
好吧
Okay.
我跟你说过我想去瑞典
I told you I wanted to go to Sweden.
不  你说的是要能去也挺好的
No, you said it would be cool to go.
是啊  然后我有机会去了
Yeah, and then I got the opportunity
-我决定要去  -我不介意你去瑞典
- and I decided to do it. - Look, I don't mind you going.
我只是希望你能告诉我  没别的
I just wish you would've told me, that's all.
我刚才已经道歉了  丹妮
Well, I just apologized, Dani.
你没有道歉  你嘴里说着对不起
You didn't apologize, you said sorry,
意思更像是"有什么办法"
which sounds more like, "Too bad."
我还是回家去吧
Maybe I should just go home.
什么  别别
What? No, no.
我只是想弄明白
I'm just trying to understand.
我只是想道歉
And I'm trying to apologize.
我不需要你道歉
And I don't need an apology.
不需要  我只是想说说这件事  没别的
I don't, I just wanted to talk about it, that's all.
我真的觉得我该走了
I really think I should just leave.
不不不  别走
No, no, no, no.
求你了  拜托  我不是想数落你
Please, please, please. I'm not... I'm not trying to attack you.
-听起来就是数落  -我没有
- It really feels like you are. - I'm not.
那...好吧  那我很抱歉
Well, then... Well, then I'm sorry.
我只是有些困惑  对不起  我...
I'm... I just got confused. I'm sorry, I...
拜托  过来  过来好吗
Please, c'mon, can you come?
-陪我坐一会儿好吗  -别这样
- Just can you come and sit with me, please? - Stop.
拜托  我们可以聊聊
Please, and we can talk about it.
真的...真的感觉很诡异  好吗
Look, it just... It just felt really weird, okay?
但我不介意  我觉得你要去瑞典是好事
But I'm fine, I think it's great that you're going to Sweden,
真的
I do.
天大的好事
I think it's amazing.
你去瑞典是为了写论文吗
Are you going for your thesis?
我都不知道论文课题是什么
I don't know what my thesis is.
我知道  去瑞典能让你...会让你...
I know and it... It can... It will...
能激发你的灵感  对吧
It can be inspiring, right?
对吧
Right?
拜托  我反应过激了  对不起
Please, I overreacted. I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道我总是想太多
I know I get paranoid.
我也不想这样
I don't mean to.
我知道我反应过激了  但我在努力振作
I know I overreacted, but I've been trying to pull myself back up,
我在努力应对惊恐不安的情绪
and ll've been trying to deal with this panic and my fears.
我不是想给你施加压力  或者埋怨你
I didn't mean to put pressure on you or to blame you for anything...
-行了  -我只是有点抓狂
- Okay. - I just got crazy for a second,
-行了  -我不是想强加到你身上
- Okay. Okay. - and I didn't mean to project.
-没关系  -对不起
- It's fine. - I'm sorry.
没关系
It's fine.
-真的对不起  -没关系
- I am sorry. - It's fine.
我本来就要邀请你和我一起去的
I was gonna ask you if you wanted to come with me.
什么
What?
-什么意思  -我刚说了
- What do you mean? - What I just said.
去瑞典
To Sweden?
你不想要我一起去
You don't want me to go.
我刚邀请你了
I just asked.
-是啊  在我崩溃之后  -你把惊喜给毁了
- Yeah, after I broke down crying. - Well, you ruined the surprise.
我本来想浪漫一下
I wanted it to be romantic.
我们去北方之前  能不能在斯德哥尔摩
In Stockholm, are there any, like, meatball sex clubs
找个经期性爱俱乐部玩玩
we should hit up before we head north?
不行  我们直接去北方
No, we're going straight north.
但也不是直接去北方吧
Not straight, straight, though, right?
我们肯定要途径斯德哥尔摩
We gotta go through Stockholm to get there.
不是  是在相反的方向
No, it's the opposite direction.
斯德哥尔摩在阿兰达机场的南边
Stockholm is south of Arlanda.
各位  是丹妮
Guys, it's Dani.
她上来了
She's coming up.
好
Okay.
-我们要把这里清理一下吗  -不用  没事
- Should we clear all this? - No, it's fine.
我邀请了丹妮一起去瑞典
I invited Dani to come to Sweden.
跟你们说一声
So you guys know.
她不会真的去的
She's not actually gonna come,
但我还是邀请她了  免得尴尬
but I invited her just to not make it weird.
你邀请了她去...
You invited her to...
但她不会去的
But she's not coming.
她不想去吗
She doesn't want to?
我邀请了她  她接受了
I invited her and she accepted,
但她不会真的去瑞典的
but she's not actually coming to Sweden.
好吧
Okay.
各位  你们知道她经历了什么
Guys, you know what she's been going through.
没事  老兄  我只是以为...
Yeah, no, dude, I just, uh, thought it was...
老兄  没人介意
Yeah, dude, nobody minds.
以为你要说其它的事  没别的
Thought you were saying something else, that's all.
那就好
Okay, that's great.
不过我们先说好  是你们叫我邀请她的
And just so we're clear, you guys told me to invite her
而且你们也知道她要来
and you all know that she's coming...
行吗
Agreed?
行
Yep.
宝贝
Babe!
各位
Guys.
忙什么呢
How's it going?
歇着呢
We're chilling.
不错
Nice.
瑞典是吧
So, Sweden.
-是啊  -你也一起去  是吧
- Yeah. - You're coming, right?
这个嘛
I mean, I...
应该是吧
I guess so,
如果你们的计划不会被我破坏的话
if that's not completely ruining you guys' plans.
-不会不会  -完全不会
- Oh, no, no. - No, not at all.
克里斯蒂安  你能不能
Christian, can I get you to take a look
过来帮我看看这段
at this paragraph real quick?
好啊
Yeah, sure.
我马上回来
I'll be back.
佩尔
Pelle.
你在画什么呢
What were you drawing?
桌子而已
Just the table.
你最近如何
How have you been?
-很好  -是吗
- Pretty good. - Yeah?
熬过了期末  你懂的
Survived finals, you know.
你呢
And you?
这学期我没上完
I didn't quite finish,
不过今年学校对我网开一面
but they're giving me a break this year.
对了  天啊  当然了  抱歉
God, yes, yes, of course. Sorry.
就是...
It's, uh...
你觉得人类学系怎么样
How did you like the Anthropology department?
我挺喜欢的
I like it, yeah.
可能不像他那么喜欢  不过...
Not as much as this one maybe, but...
你学的是精神病学  对吧
You're doing psychiatry, right?
心理学  是的
Psychology, yeah.
-好的  -学心理的都是疯子
- Okay. - That's how you know I'm nuts.
是啊  而且你的眼神很古怪
Yeah, also that funny look in your eye.
你要一起去海尔辛兰
So you're coming to Halsingland?
应该是吧
I guess so, yeah.
而且我们到的那天是我的生日
And, um, we'll actually be arriving on my birthday.
-生日快乐  -谢谢
- Well, happy birthday. - Thank you!
克里斯蒂安说你安排了一周的特别活动
Yeah, Christian says you've got this special week planned.
是的  我家人要庆祝一个为期九天的疯狂节日
Yeah, it's sort of a crazy nine-day festival my family's doing.
各种庆典
Lots of pageantry...
特殊仪式  还要盛装打扮
special ceremonies, and dressing up.
听起来很有趣
That sounds fun.
看起来可能会很傻
It'll probably seem very silly.
不过有点像戏剧
But, it's like theater.
克里斯蒂安说你
Yeah, Christian says you're...
你是在一个公社长大的  是吗
You're from like a commune, right?
是的  我们是一个小社群
Yeah, we're... We're a small community.
来  我给你看
Here. I'll show you.
我明白你说的庆典是什么意思了
I see what you mean about the pageantry.
这些服装是为每年的冬至和夏至
Yeah, we make those clothes special for every
特别制作的
winter and summer solstice.
基本上做什么事大家都在一起
I mean, everybody sort of does everything together.
这个符号很有意思
That's an interesting symbol.
是的  我们都要学卢恩字母
Yeah, we're taught the Runic alphabet, so...
这是谁
Who's that one?
这是去年的五月女王
That's last year's May Queen.
真漂亮
Beautiful.
你要去参加我非常开心
You know, I'm very, very glad you're coming.
我觉得这是一件好事
I... I think it's very good you're coming.
谢谢
Thank you.
而且我
Also, I...
我之前都没有机会告诉你
I never had the chance to tell you...
但是我
but I was...
听到你失去亲人的消息我很难过
I was so very sorry to hear about your loss.
发生那样的事
What happened, I mean,
我简直无法想象
I can't even imagine.
我是说
I mean...
-我也失去了父母  所以...  -好吧
- I lost my parents, too, so... - Okay.
我大概能体会
I kind of have some idea.
-抱歉  -不
- I'm sorry. - No!
-不  是我抱歉  -不  你...
- No, I'm sorry. - No, you're...
我要去一下洗手间  谢谢
I'm gonna just go to the bathroom, thank you.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我们即将开始降落  抵达目的地斯德哥尔摩
we are beginning our initial descent into Stockholm...
天呐  这里的女人
Oh, my God, the women here.
为什么比别处更性感
What is it that makes them hotter?
维京人把其他国家最漂亮的美女
The Vikings grabbed all the best babes from other countries and
都抢来了这里
dragged them over.
要开多久
How long is the drive?
大概四小时
About four hours.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我看了个视频  不是假的
I saw a video, and it wasn't even like... it wasn't fake.
有个女人  她有三个阴蒂
And there was this one woman with three clits.
真的  不骗你
Actually. For real.
对广岛敏感
Sensitive about Hiroshima.
我还真是
I am, actually.
-泪痕呢  -是的
- Trail of tears? - Yeah.
-奴隶制呢  -老兄  你觉得呢
- Slavery? - Dude, what do you think...
想象一下  这男的在读新闻
Like, imagine trying to take a dude seriously
你明知他用平底锅打老婆
and he's, like, reading out the news
还得努力把他当回事儿
and you know he, like, bludgeoned his wife with a pan.
艾米
我发早了  不过生日快乐
希望明天一切顺利
乌萨克学说认为卢恩字母是一种密码
乌萨克之秘密纳粹语言
你为什么要看这个
Why are you reading that.
问佩尔
Ask pelle.
我们村里的人都要学卢恩字母
We're taught the runic alphabet in my village,
所以乔希随身带着那本书来气我
so Josh just carries that around to annoy me.
你的论文课题是什么来着
What are you doing your thesis on again.
主要是关于欧洲仲夏节传统的
Well, my focus is actually on European midsummer traditions,
也就是我们这趟旅行的动力
which was basically the impetus for this whole trip that we're all on.
这听起来和你想研究的差不多  对吧
Hey, that sounds similar to what you're thinking of doing, right?
你论文要写的
For your thesis.
你知道的  我还不知道论文要写什么
Well, I don't know exactly what I'm doing it on yet, as you know.
不过我在考虑写斯堪的纳维亚相关的  是的
But I'm thinking of rooting it in something Scandinavian, yeah.
看见没  佩尔
See that, pelle.
你成功把所有朋友都洗脑了
You've managed to brainwash all of your friends.
乔希早就被洗脑了  用不着我
Josh was already brainwashed when I found him.
海尔辛兰
好了  这里是第一站
Okay, this is the first stop.
我们到了吗
This is it?
还没到  不过快了
Not quite, almost.
佩尔
Pelle!
-真美  -天呐
- Just beautiful. - Oh, my God.
各位  这些是我们村里的年轻人
Hey, guys, so these are younger people from my village.
他们也刚刚从外面的世界回来
They're also returning from their trips outside.
过来吧
Come on over.
这些是我的美国朋友
These are my friends from America.
老兄
Dude.
赶紧过来
Just fucking walk.
老兄  这里虫子太多
Yeah, dude, there's so many bugs.
很美吧
It's beautiful, huh?
这几位是
Okay, so this is, uh...
马克  丹妮
Mark, Dani...
克里斯蒂安和乔希
Christian and Josh.
怎么了
What?
稍等我一下
Give me just one second.
你觉得他认识那个人吗
You think he knows that guy?
他听起来很生气
He sounded mad.
肯定是好话
That must be good.
来  快过来
Here! Come on over, come on over.
这些是我在美国的好朋友
This is, uh, these are my great friends from America.
克里斯蒂安  丹妮
Christian, Dani,
乔希和马克
Josh, and Mark.
这是我兄弟  英格马
Meet my brother, Ingemar.
我们从小就是最好的哥们
Best friends since we were babies, actually.
克里斯蒂安  乔希  马克
So, Christian, Josh, Mark...
-丹妮  对  -对
- Dani? Yeah! - Yeah!
太棒了  跟我的朋友打个招呼吧
Awesome! And say hello to my friends.
这是来自伦敦的
This is Simon and Connie
-西蒙和康妮  -你好吗
- from London. - How's it going?
-你好  -西蒙  这是佩尔
- Hi. - Simon, this is Pelle...
这边是我两秒前
And these are all the names
刚认识的那批人
I just learned two seconds ago.
对了  你们来得正是时候
Perfect timing, by the way,
我们五分钟前刚吃了这个
We... we just took these five minutes ago.
还没嗨起来呢
Haven't even started coming up yet.
我去
Oh, shit!
你们是想先吃还是先安顿下来
Do you guys wanna take it now or should we settle in first?
管它呢  我们现在就吃吧
Fuck it, let's just take it now, right?
-行  -好
- Yeah. Yeah. - Great.
那个
You know what,
如果可以的话  我想先落脚
I might have to find my footing first if that's okay.
-好  没问题  -那就好
- Yeah, of course. - Yeah? Okay.
听好  要是你觉得不妥
And listen, if you're feeling uneasy,
根本就不用吃
you don't have to take them at all.
不不不  我只想先安顿下来
No. No, no, no. I just... I wanna feel settled first.
-好  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
-我等你  -不  不用  你吃吧
- I'll wait. - No, no, you go ahead.
-不  我等你  -拜托
- No, I'll wait. - Please.
我想和你一起嗨
I want us to come up together.
-准备好了吗  -好吗
- Ready? - Okay?
各位  我要等丹妮  你们先吃吧
Guys, I'm gonna wait for Dani, so you just go ahead.
老兄  我们不能在不同的时间吃
Dude, we can't take them at different times,
嗨的步调会错开的
they'll be totally separate trips.
那你想等我们吗
You wanna wait for us then?
算了  没关系  没关系
You know what, it's fine, it's fine.
-宝贝  宝贝  不  -我准备好了
- Babe... Babe, no. - I'm ready.
-不  没关系  -没人逼你
- No, it's okay, - Don't feel rushed.
没有  没有  没关系  我准备好了
I don't, I don't. It's fine, I'm ready.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
确定  马克  谢谢
Yes, Mark, thank you.
他们沏了致幻蘑菇茶
They've made mushroom tea.
要是你不喜欢这口味可以喝那个
If you prefer against the taste.
好  我就喝那个吧  谢谢
Yeah, okay, I'll try that, thank you.
-你叫因格马还是英格马  -英格马
- Ingemar? Ingemar? - Ingemar.
-英格马  好的  谢谢  -很好
- Ingemar, okay. Thank you. - Perfect.
-别让马克逼你  -他没有
- Don't let Mark be the one to pressure you. - He's not.
-唯独他不行  -他没有  没有
- Of all people. - He's not, he's not.
这样简单点  没事
It will... It will get complicated otherwise, it's fine.
-准备好了吗  -好了  谢谢
- Are you ready? - Yes, thank you.
给你
There you go.
谢了  老兄
Thanks, dude.
好  我们开始吧
Okay, here we go then.
-想点快乐的事  -你确定吗
- Think happy thoughts! - Are you sure about this?
-确定  确定  我很兴奋  -干杯
- Yeah. Yeah, I'm excited. - Cheers!
-好吧  -好吗
- All right. - Yeah?
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
我觉得会好玩的
I think it's gonna be fun.
-开始吧  -好  开始
- We're in? - Yep, go.
现在几点了
What time is it?
晚上九点
It's 9:00 p.m.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
不可能是九点  天还是蓝的
That can't be right! The sky is blue!
正常  这里是瑞典
It's fine, it's Sweden.
这不正常  怎么会这样
That's not fine! Why is it like that?
没事的  马克  这是午夜的阳光
It's okay, Mark. It's the midnight sun.
这太奇怪了  我不喜欢这样
That feels wrong, I don't like that!
我向你保证这没问题
I promise you, it's okay.
我不觉得没问题
I'm not okay.
见鬼  又一个生面孔
Oh, fuck, it's a new person.
什么
What?
我现在不想见生人
I don't want new people right now.
不  有新面孔是好事  马克
No, new people are good, Mark.
你们好
Hi, hi!
我要躺下来  行吗
I'm just gonna lay down, okay?
行  躺吧
Yeah, do that.
你们也都躺下来
Everybody else lay down.
各位  躺吧  感觉特别好
Guys, do it, it feels so nice.
乔希  你能躺下来吗
Josh, can you lie down, please?
你们感觉到了吗
Can you feel that?
能量
The energy.
从大地中传来
Coming up from the earth.
看
Look!
树木也在呼吸
The trees too, they're breathing.
大自然本能地知晓
Nature just knows instinctively
如何保持和谐
how to stay in harmony.
万物都有条不紊地运转
Everything just mechanically doing its part.
你们就像我的家人
You guys are like my family.
你们就像我真正的家人  血亲
You're like my real, actual family.
丹妮
Dani?
抱歉
Sorry.
我要散散步
I'm gonna go for a walk.
我也陪你散步吧
I can walk, too.
不用了
No, I'm good.
不不不不
No, no, no, no.
别想那个  你没事
Don't think that. You're fine.
快到你的生日了
It's almost your birthday.
你没事  你很好  你很好
You're okay, you're fine. You're fine.
快停下  我没事
Stop it! I'm fine.
丹妮
Hey, Dani!
你好吗
How are you?
他们在嘲笑我
They were laughing at me.
什么  不不不  他们肯定不是嘲笑你
What? No, no, no, I'm sure they weren't.
他们一直在笑
They've been laughing.
想见见我的朋友吗
Want to come meet my friends?
谢谢  对不起  谢谢
Thank you. I'm sorry, thank you.
停  停  操
Stop it! Stop it, fuck!
你没事  你没事  你没事
You're okay, you're okay, you're okay.
我睡了多久
How long was I asleep?
我们大概六小时前在这里找到你的
I mean, we found you here, like, six hours ago.
天黑过吗
Did it get dark at all?
暗过几个小时  但没有完全黑
For a couple of hours, not completely.
现在是明天吗
Is it tomorrow?
从昨天算的话是的
I mean, from yesterday's perspective.
来吧
Come on.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
去要去的地方
What we came for.
老天  佩尔  你要带我们去哪
Jesus, Pelle, where are you taking us?
这地方也太远了吧
Yeah, this is way the hell out there.
瑞典有蜱虫吗
Do they have ticks in Sweden?
瑞典的蜱虫问题很严峻
Sweden has a tick problem.
什么
What?
没这回事吧  真的吗
No they don't, do they really?
蜱虫真是个大问题
Actually, it is a big problem.
去年夏天  感染森林脑炎的人数
Last summer, a record number of people
创了历史新高
got tick-borne encephalitis.
什么鬼  你说真的吗
What the fuck? Are you serious?
我祖父母都死于蜱虫病
Both my grandparents died from ticks.
葬礼上都不能打开棺材
Had to give them a closed casket funeral.
乔希  我还真有个得莱姆病的叔叔
Okay, Josh, I actually have an uncle with Lyme.
相信我  如果你问他
And believe me, if you ask him,
他会说为野餐付出的代价太惨重了
it was not worth the pleasant picnic in the park.
他完蛋了
He's fucked.
就是这里了
So, this is the place.
宁静而庄严的哈加
The tranquil and majestic Harga.
佩尔  这些人你都认识吗
Pelle, you know all these people?
他们是我的家人
These are my family!
我们要先在邪教阵地逗留
So we're stopping in Waco
然后再去佩尔的村子吗
before going to Pelle's village?
谢谢
Thank you!
-谢谢  -这是什么  草莓吗
- Thank you. - What is it? Strawberry?
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thanks.
包给我吧
This bag?
谢谢  抱歉
Thank you... uh, sorry.
各位
Hey, guys?
来认识一下我的姐妹  戴格妮
Meet my sister, Dagny.
和我同一天出生的
Born the exact same day as me.
这几位是丹妮  乔希  马克  克里斯蒂安
Dani, Josh, Mark, Christian.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Tack! - Thank you.
谢谢
Tack.
奥德老爹
Father Odd!
抱歉  这几位是我的朋友
Sorry, these are my friends.
克里斯蒂安  丹妮  乔希  马克
Christian, Dani, Josh, Mark.
你好
Hello.
你好  你好
Hello, hello.
欢迎  欢迎
Welcome, welcome.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
你们的到来让我们非常高兴
We are so very happy to have you.
谢谢
Thank you.
佩尔看人的眼光很精准
Pelle has an immaculate sense for people.
我喜欢你的服装
I... I love what you're wearing.
我的罩袍吗
My frock?
很女气对吧
Yeah, quite girly, no?
我们这么穿是为了表达对约弥尔的敬意
We do these as a tribute in respect of Ymir
也是因为大自然的
and because of the nature's
属性是雌雄同体
hermaphrodite, I think, qualities. Yeah.
布拉吉的撒基斯圣人
I think the Sakhis saints do the same thing
撒基斯是印度教苦行僧的一派
布拉吉据传是奎师那的诞生地 是印度教圣城
撒基斯会穿女装  装扮成奎师那的女伴
也是这么做的吧
in Brajbhoomi?
你们是客人
So, we are your hosts.
需要什么尽管说
So whatever you need, just say so
我们会安排的  好吗
and we will accommodate, okay?
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
今天大家都在欢庆
Today is all festivities.
明天  正式的仪式就开始了
Just tomorrow, the official ceremony begin
欢迎你们参加
and you are welcome!
-欢迎  欢迎  欢迎  -谢谢
- Welcome, welcome, welcome. - Thank you.
玩得开心点
Yeah. Enjoy.
谢谢
Just... thank you.
那家伙脸真红
That guy has a very red face.
是吧
Yeah?
-这是吃的吗  -是的
- Do we eat these? - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-我能拍照吗  -悄悄拍
- Can I take photos? - Discreetly.
谢谢
Thanks.
请原谅
Forgive me.
我忘记了那些不会说瑞典语的人
I'm excluding the ones who aren't of Swedish tongue.
欢迎来到哈加
Welcome to Harga,
仲夏节快乐
and happy midsummer!
距离上次大祭已经过去了九十年
It has been 90 years since our last great feast
下次大祭则还要等九十年
and it will be 90 years before our next.
最棒的是  这是有记录以来
And what poetry that it's now the hottest
最热  最明亮的夏天
and brightest summer on record.
我们已经有了如此多的可回馈之物
We already have so much to give back
废话就不多说了
and so, without any further blathering,
让我们举起酒杯
let's raise our glasses.
揭开九日祭典的帷幕
Let our Nine-Day feast commence.
干杯
Skål!
我焰将止  不再燃烧
灵魂  回归死者
自从我出生以来  那堆火就没熄灭过
You know, that fire hasn't burned out since I was born.
让它持续燃烧是我们的职责
It's all of our jobs to keep it going.
是的
Yeah.
等等  你说什么
Wait, what did you say?
我晚点再告诉你
I'll tell you later.
他在感恩
He's giving thanks.
为了食物
For the food.
嗯  还有天气和庄稼
Yeah, and the weather and the crops.
刚刚那是祈祷吗
Was that praying?
可能不算祈祷  但他是在说...
Maybe not praying, but he was just addressing the...
世间万物  和谐与平衡
The everything... The Harmony and the balance.
能给我一份唱词的翻译吗
Can I get a translation of what was sung?
好的  我之后可以向他要
Yeah, I can get a translation from him later.
好的  谢了  那就太好了
Yeah, thanks. That would be amazing.
没问题
Sure.
是的  谢谢  佩尔
Yes. Thank you, pelle.
别客气
Of course.
你们应该加入的
You guys should join.
不  我太害怕了
No, I'm too scared.
-好了  -谢了  宝贝
- All right. - Thanks, babe.
那些孩子在玩什么
What are the kids playing?
剥愚人的皮
Skin the fool.
-剥愚人的皮  -对
- Skin the fool? - Yeah.
真棒
Precious.
佩尔  任何人都能加入吗
Hey, Pelle, can anybody just join in?
你是个美国佬  你直接冲进去就行
You're an American, just jam yourself in there.
好
All right.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
天啊  佩尔
Oh, my gosh, Pelle.
别人生日我都会画的
Just something I do for birthdays.
或许有点不合适
Maybe it's not appropriate?
不不不  完全不会  非常感谢
No, no, no, no, not at all. Thank you so much.
真的很美
It's beautiful.
我们俩知道就行了
Anyway, just between us.
是啊
Yeah, well...
反正克里斯蒂安都忘了  所以真的很赞  谢谢
Christian forgot anyway, so this is amazing. Thank you.
不不不  是我忘了提醒他
No. No, no, no, I forgot to remind him
不是他的错
and it's not his fault, it's...
没关系
Never mind, it's okay.
这太美了
This is beautiful.
非常感谢你  我非常感动
Thank you so much, I'm really touched.
你们是怎么维持这里的
So, how do you support this place?
伐木  织布  顺势疗法
Lumbering, linen, homeopathics...
水力发电场
Water power plant.
那边在上课
School time over here.
刻卢恩字母
Carving runes?
真的吗
Really?
他们把它放在枕头下面  梦想着它的力量
They put it under their pillow and dream about its powers.
对  我也这么做
Oh, yeah. I do that, too.
靠  有个大家伙
Fuck. There's a big one.
我去
Shit.
上面是什么文字
What alphabet is that from?
早期弗赛克文
The Younger Futhark.
我觉得是  或者是中世纪吗
I... I think? Or is that medieval?
其实是晚期弗赛克文
Actually, that is the Elder Futhark.
你们俩在一起多久了
So, how long have you two been together?
天啊  我想想
Oh, geez, um...
三年半多一点
Just over three and a half years.
四年
Four years.
-不对吧  真的吗  -对
- No? Really? - Yeah.
还有两周就四年了
Four years in two weeks.
你是对的  对不起
You're right, I'm sorry.
没错  是四年
You're right. Four years.
嗯  你们怎么认识的
Yeah, um, how did you guys all meet?
我们在同一个农场工作
We were all working on the same farm
有意思的是  西蒙和我刚成为朋友的时候
and funny enough, I was dating Connie
我和康妮在谈恋爱
when Simon and me first became pals.
我们就约会了一次
Well, we'd been on a date.
当时我都不知道那是个约会
And I didn't even actually know it was a date, so...
你说得对  不  没有
You're right. No, no.
我的意思是康妮和我刚成为朋友
I meant that Connie and me had just become friends.
我们  我们决定做朋友
We... We decided to be friends.
就在康妮和西蒙开始谈恋爱之前
And that was just before Connie and Simon started dating.
现在他们订婚了
And now they're engaged.
什么  恭喜
What? Congratulations!
确实很棒  恭喜
Which is amazing, yes, congratulations.
谢谢  我们请英格玛
Yeah, thanks. Yeah, we actually asked Ingemar
来主持婚礼
to officiate the wedding.
-真的吗  -假的
- Really? - Nah.
那个房子是干什么的
What's that building over there?
那是圣殿
It's like a sacred temple,
但禁止入内
but no one's allowed in there.
我带你们去看我们休息的地方
Let me show you where we sleep.
我带你们去看颠倒树
Let me show you the Rotvalta!
我们就无视那头熊吗
So we're just gonna ignore the bear then?
的确是一头熊
It's a bear.
那是什么
What's that?
-我们可以去看看  -好
- We can check it out. - Yeah.
爱情故事
Love story.
什么
What?
天呐
Oh, man.
就像圣经一样
It's like in the Scripture.
你们觉得怎么样
What do you think?
就像是另一个世界
It's like another world.
美轮美奂
Amazing.
大家就在这里睡吗
People just sleep here?
没错  36岁以下的年轻人都睡在这里
Yeah, all the younger ones until we turn 36
然后我们就搬进工人的房子里
and then we move to the laborers house.
为什么是36岁
Why 36?
我们觉得人生就像四季
Well, we think of life like the seasons.
18岁之前你还是孩子  那是春季
So you're a child until you're 18 and that's Spring.
然后在18到36岁的某个时刻
And then at some point, we all do our Pilgrimage
我们都要踏上朝圣之旅
which is between 18 and 36.
那是夏季  然后从36岁到54岁
That's Summer, and then from 36 to 54,
我们步入了工作的年龄  那是秋季
we're working age, which is Fall.
最终54到72岁时你就成了导师
And then finally from 54 to 72 you become a mentor.
72岁会发生什么
What happens at 72?
这里没什么隐私
Not a lot of privacy.
是啊  如果要自慰的话怎么办
Yeah, what do you do when you need to jerk off?
尤其是墙上还有这么多阴茎
Especially with all these dicks on the wall.
很多阴茎
There's a lot of dicks.
你看  那家伙不听我说
See, man, that guy dismissed me,
但这与锡克教圣徒或阿佛洛狄特斯崇拜一模一样
but this is exactly like the sakhis saints and the cult of Aphroditus.
童年  春季
朝圣  夏季
劳动  秋季
指导  冬季
卢恩字母
你可能忘了一件事
Maybe you forgot or something.
-今天是丹妮的生日  -天  谢谢
- It's Dani's birthday today. - Oh, thank you.
她说什么了吗
Did she say something?
没有  什么都没说
No, no, no, absolutely not.
我只是想提前告诉你...
I just wanted to let you know before, so...
这些是五月女王吗
Are these the May Queens?
是的
Yeah.
对  你们之后会看到的
Right. You'll actually be here for that.
你们的五月女王都是谁
And who are your May Queens?
每年仲夏  我们都有舞蹈比赛
Every mid-summer, we have this dance competition
赢家会被加冕  这是
and the winner gets crowned and this is...
孩子们在看《王牌大贱谍》  要一起看吗
在南边的房子
她刚刚...
Was that...
你也看到了吧
You saw that too, right?
佩尔  她是谁
Pelle, who was that?
英格
Inge.
天呐  我想给她洗个澡
Oh, my God, I want to give her a bath.
能借一步说话吗
Can I pull you outside for a sec?
没问题
Yeah, sure.
佩尔  叫她回来
Pelle, tell her to come back.
♪ 祝你生日快乐 ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
什么
What?
♪ 祝你生日快乐 ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ 祝亲爱的丹妮生日快乐 ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Dani ♪
♪ 祝你生日快乐 ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
操
Fuck.
-停  别点了  -怎么了
- Stop, it's fine. - What?
你不会以为我忘了吧
You didn't think I forgot, did you?
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起我被这里的日照弄糊涂了
I'm sorry I got fucked up by the daylight
我以为还是昨天
and I thought it was yesterday.
-没关系  没事的  -生日快乐
- It's okay. It's fine. - Happy birthday.
-生日快乐  -谢谢  我没生气  没关系
- Happy birthday. - Thank you. I'm not upset. It's okay.
-你应该生气的  -我应该的
- You should be. - I... I should be.
对不起
I'm sorry.
好了  赶紧睡美容觉
All right, beauty rest.
明天是个大日子
Tomorrow's a big day.
明天有什么事
What's tomorrow?
第一场大仪式
First of the big ceremonies.
阿特斯图帕
Attestupa.
那是什么
What's that?
很难解释
It's too hard to explain,
你明天就会明白了
you'll get a better sense tomorrow.
-等等  真的吗  -你不能现在就告诉我吗
- Wait, seriously? - You can't just tell me now?
等等  你不是说真的那个吧
Wait, you're not talking about an actual one?
谷歌搜索  阿特斯图帕
挺真的
I mean, it's pretty actual.
未连接网络
操
Fuck.
你知道那是什么吗
Do you know what it is?
老兄
Dude!
可怕吗
Is it scary?
真他妈烦人
That is so fucking annoying.
帮我检查头皮上有没有蜱虫
Check my scalp for ticks,
然后我帮你检查
then I'll check yours.
应该来个人告诉那些姑娘
Somebody should tell those girls
她们走路的方向反了
they're walking stupid.
他们一般要站多久
How long do they typically stand?
我们要站到可以坐下为止
We're going to stand until it's right to sit.
这是给我的吗
Are these for me?
-你是倒退着采的吗  -是的
- You pick 'em backwards? - Yeah.
就是那两个人吗
Are those the ones?
对
Yeah.
老兄  我好饿
Dude, I'm so hungry.
就好像他们是故意把饭弄得这么恶心
It's like they're trying to make it gross.
老兄
Dude...
之前那个女孩又在盯着我看了
Is the girl from earlier staring at me again.
-是吧  -是的
- Yeah. - Yeah.
她的母亲在进行朝圣之旅
Her... Her mother is on Pilgrimage.
有助于让她脱离母亲的怀抱
Helps her to detach.
好的
Okay.
这里的婴儿由大家抚养
The babies are raised here by everyone.
你想要吗
You want this?
你说如果我现在把手指
What do you think that guy's reaction would be
捅进那家伙的屁股  他会作何反应
if I just put my finger in his butt right now?
你要跟他们一起去吗
Dude, are you following them out?
我太困了  我要去眯一下
I'm beat. I'm gonna go take a nap.
-好的  -好
- Okay, okay. Yeah. - Yeah.
等等  我们现在要干什么
Wait, what're we doing now?
那本书是什么
What is that book?
《鲁比拉达》  我们的圣典
Rubi Radr. Our scripture.
我能读吗
Can I read that?
你读不了
You would not be able.
天啊
Oh, my God!
没事的
It's fine.
她是跳下来了吗
Did she jump?
搞什么
What the...
瑞典的一些悬崖被称为阿特斯图帕
据说这代表着这些悬崖
古时被用于举行老人自杀仪式
不能自理或支撑家计的长者
会跳下或被推下悬崖
这是仪式的一部分
It's part of the ceremony.
什么  不  她是掉下来的
What? No, she fell, she fell.
操
Fuck!
-她是掉下来的  对吧  -她是不是跳下来了
- She fell, right? - Did she jump?
没事的
It's okay.
天啊  她是掉下来了还是跳下来了
Oh, my... Did she fall or did she jump?
没事的  没关系  不要担心
It's okay, it's fine. Don't worry.
没事是什么意思
What do you mean it's fine?
她死了  看她的头
She's fucking dead. Look at her head!
看她的头  她死了
Look at her head, she's dead!
这是仪式的一部分
It's a part of the ceremony.
你怎么就这么站在这里
Why the fuck are you standing there like that?
她从悬崖上跳下来了
She just fucking jumped off the cliff.
你是瞎了吗  这他妈什么鬼
Are you freaking blind? What the... Fuck!
天啊
Oh, my God.
什么鬼
What the fuck?
不  他  他也要跳了
No, he's doing... He's doing the same thing.
他也要跳了
He's doing the same fucking thing!
拦住他  先生  别这么做
Someone stop! Sir, don't do it.
让他停下
Tell him to stop.
大家怎么都站着不动  怎么回事
Why's everyone just standing there, what the fuck?
先生  别  别跳  别跳
Sir, don't... Don't jump, don't jump!
拜托  谁能让他别跳下来
Please, someone tell him not to jump.
-搞什么  -谁能...
- What the fuck? - Someone tell him...
-他还活着  -怎么回事
- He's still alive. - What's going on?
他还活着
He's fucking alive!
至少做点什么吧
At least try somehing!
天啊
Oh my God!
妈的  我们走
Fuck, we're going.
-妈的  活见鬼  -去哪里
- Fuck! This is fucked! - Where?
去你们的  你们都疯了
Fuck this! You're fucked!
妈的  你们就他妈站在这看着
Fuck! You're all just fucking standing there watching,
英格马  你没提醒他们吗
你们都有什么毛病
what the fuck is wrong with you?
对不起  希芙祖母  我试过了
-拜托  拜托  -不  离她远点
- Please! Please! - No, fucking leave her alone!
拜托  听我说  听我解释
Please, listen to me. Let me explain!
什么  解释什么
What? Explain what?
-拜托  可怜的孩子  -都疯了
- Please, my poor thing. - Fucked!
拜托  你们刚刚看到的
Please! What you just saw
是一项历史非常悠久的习俗
is a long, long, long observed custom.
-"习俗"  你们疯了  -是的
- "Custom!" It's fucked! - Yes.
刚才跳崖的两位
Those two who jumped
刚刚到达了哈加生命周期的终点
have just reached the end of their Harga life-cycle.
你们得理解这对他们而言是莫大的喜悦
And you need to understand it as a great joy for them.
-"喜悦"  -是的  等轮到我的时候
- "Joy?" - Yes, and when it is my turn,
我也会体验莫大的喜悦
it will be a great joy for me.
-妈的  -我们把生命视作一个圆
- Fuck. - We view life as a circle,
一个循环
a recycle.
刚才跳崖的那位女士  她叫于尔娃对吗
The lady who jumped, her name was Ylva, yes?
那边那个尚未出生的孩子
And that baby over there who is not yet born
会继承这个名字
will inherit that name.
我们不会老去
Instead of getting old
在痛苦  恐惧与羞耻中死亡
and dying in pain and fear and shame,
相反  我们奉献出自己的生命
we give our life.
作为一种姿态
As a gesture.
-姿态  -在生命崩坏之前
- A gesture? - Before it can spoil.
死亡没有好处
It does no good dying,
向无可避免之事作出反抗
lashing back at the inevitable.
那会让灵魂腐坏
It corrupts the spirit.
很抱歉我没有好好提醒你们
I'm so sorry I didn't warn you better.
你还好吗
You feeling okay?
我只是需要马上离开这里
I just really need to not be here right now.
嗯
Yeah.
我离开一下
I'm gonna go.
给自己一点时间  好吗
Just take some time to yourself, okay.
第八个
Number 8...
布鲁塞尔的一位商人在高速公路上开车时
A businessman in Brussels was receiving oral sex from his secretary
他的秘书在车里给他口交
in his car while driving on the freeway.
不幸的是  他需要急刹车  结果被追尾了
Unfortunately, he needed to make a sudden stop and was rear-ended,
惊得女秘书狠狠一口咬下去
startling his protegee into biting down with such...
仪式怎么样
How was the thing?
以致于他的阴茎被干脆地咬断了
...brute force that his penis was severed clean from his body.
希望你吃得开心
Hope you enyoyed the meal...
怎么样  伙计
What's up, man?
你收得到信号吗
Are you getting reception here?
我等会儿...等会儿再跟你说
I'll talk to you in... in just a minute.
老兄
Hey, dude...
真是见鬼  是吧
Holy shit, right?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
那就好
Good.
听我说
Hey, listen.
我一直在考虑
I've been thinking about something
有件事想问你
that I wanted to ask you.
或者应该说  想告诉你
Or tell you, actually.
我一直在考虑我的论文
I've been thinking a lot about my thesis.
然后
And,
我决定要以哈加为课题
I've decided I'm gonna do it here. On Harga.
我想先告诉你一下
And I wanted to tell you first.
这样你就不会觉得我有意瞒着你
Just so it didn't seem like I wasn't telling you.
我不确定你是不是在开玩笑
I feel like... I feel like I can't tell if you're joking.
我是说
I mean... I mean,
你知道仲夏节是我的论文课题
you know I'm doing my thesis on midsummer.
-所以我才要来这里  -嗯
- That's the reason why I'm here. - Yeah.
嗯  但不是写这个社群
Yeah, but not on this community.
接下来你还要去德国和英格兰
I mean, you're going to Germany and England next.
你肯定知道我想写这个
Well, you knew I was gonna wanna do this.
-不  我不知道  -天啊
- No, I didn't. - Oh, my God.
你难道不是刚刚才决定的吗
I mean, did you even know until just now?
克里斯蒂安  你当然知道
Christian, of course you did!
你以为我看不透
Okay, do you think I don't know
你的伎俩吗
what you're doing?
明目张胆到都有点过分了
It's actually kind of outrageously unsubtle.
你居然这么不要脸
The fact that you're being this bald about it.
我还挺佩服你的
I'm... I'm honestly kind of impressed.
什么鬼  你说什么呢
What the fuck, man? What does that mean?
对啊  什么鬼
Yeah, what the fuck!
我一直在研究这个  你心知肚明
This is what I've been working toward and you know it.
所以你现在满脸内疚  因为你明白
That's why you look so guilty right now, because you know.
你明白自己的行为
You know that what you're doing
不道德且懒惰  是占便宜
is unethical and leechy and lazy.
说实话  还有点可悲
And, frankly, it's kind of sad.
-去你的  -不  老兄  别说我
- Fuck you! - No, dude, not fuck me!
找你自己的课题去
Find your own subject.
或是你自己的兴趣
Or... Or your own passion.
因为  好吧听着
And, because... All right, look.
这个研究我真的很投入
I am... I'm actually invested in this.
这不是什么好听的
This is not some glorified hobby
随便玩玩的爱好
that I'm casually dipping my feet into.
行了
Okay.
殿下  您可能没注意到
In case you hadn't noticed, your highness,
我们都是博士研究生
we're doing the exact same degree.
但态度完全不同  克里斯蒂安
No, but not in the same way, Christian.
懂吗  什么事都得我手把手教你
Okay? I have to hold your little hand through everything.
要不是我教你  你连期刊网站都不会用
You didn't even know how to use JSTOR until I taught you,
你他妈可是研究生啊
and you are a fucking grad student.
你到底为什么搞学术
Why are you even in academia?
你根本不在乎  这没问题  这是你的自由
You don't care! Which is fine. That is your prerogative.
但你别想抢我的心血走捷径
But do not appropriate my actual work for your new shortcut.
我的论文要写这里
I'm gonna do my thesis here.
如果你也有一样的打算
If you're gonna do it here too,
我不介意与你合作
I'm open to collaborating.
如果你不愿意
And if not,
那我们就各写各的  都写哈加
I guess we can both do separate theses on the Hargas.
老兄  我居然一觉睡过了那么精彩的事
Dude, of all the things to let me sleep through.
什么
What?
我们明天早上就走
We're leaving tomorrow morning.
我知道
I know we are.
抱歉  你好  我不想打扰你
Sorry, um... Hi. I don't mean to disturb you.
你好
Hello.
你好  我叫克里斯蒂安
Hi, I'm Christian.
你好  我叫乌拉
Hello. My name is Ulla.
-乌拉  -乌拉  她叫玛雅
- Ulla. - Ulla. And this is Maja.
玛雅  你好
Maja, hi.
你们在做什么
What are you guys doing?
我们在装饰这棵树
We are decorating the tree.
嗯  我能不能问你一个问题
Right. Um, I was wondering if I could ask you a question.
-可以  -你看过...
- Of course. - How many...
你看过几次阿特斯图帕...仪式
How many times have you seen Attestupa... performed?
-阿特斯图帕  -阿特斯图帕
- "Attestupa." - "Attestupa."
你看过几次仪式
How many times you've seen it performed?
有人达到年龄就会举行  所以...
Every time one reaches age, so...
-好吧  -很多次
- Okay. - A lot.
好的
Okay.
你们通常有没有  哀悼的阶段
And do you have a typical... period of grieving?
哀悼一段时间
Is there a-a time when you mourn?
我们哀悼并庆祝
We grieve and celebrate.
-是的  -好的  明白了
- Yes. - Okay. I see.
我已经跟克里斯蒂安说了
I told Christian this already,
我觉得他想装成这是他自己想出来的
and now I think he's trying to pretend like it's his idea,
-所以如果他来找你...  -不
- so if he comes up to you... - Well, no,
等一下  我真的不认为
wait a minute. I... I seriously doubt that
长老们会允许你们留下书面记录
the elders will approve of anything being written down.
他们的保护欲非常强
They're extremely protective.
好吧  那我就全用假名代替
Okay, so then, I'll just use aliases for everything.
-问题解决了  -那还有什么意义
- Problem solved. - Then what would be the point?
你甚至都不能进行同行评审
You couldn't even get it peer reviewed.
顺便一提  克里斯蒂安已经问过我了
And Christian did already ask me this, by the way,
我的回答是一样的
and I told him the same thing I'm telling you now.
你不是说没跟他谈过吗
I thought you said you hadn't talked to him.
该死  不是
Fuck. No.
好吧  我会去问长老们
Okay, look, uh, I'll ask the elders.
-行吗  -行
- Okay? Good. - Yep.
丹妮
Dani?
我真的很抱歉  佩尔
I'm really sorry, Pelle.
感谢你邀请我来  但我  我真得走了
Thank you for inviting me, but I... I really have to go.
有人能开车送我一下吗
Can someone maybe drive me somewhere?
我知道我不该让你看到那一幕
I know I shouldn't have let you stay for that.
我知道看起来很极端  但我们只是...
I mean, I know it looks extreme. But we only...
我不明白我为什么来这里  佩尔
I don't know why I'm here, Pelle!
我不明白你为什么邀请我们来
I don't know why you invited us.
我不明白  我不明白为什么...
I don't know. I don't know why...
-我不明白我为什么来这里  -没事没事
- I don't know why I'm here. - Okay, okay, okay.
-没事的  没关系  -我不明白  我不...
- It's fine. It's okay. - I don't know and I can't...
-来  来  坐下  -不
- Come on. Come on, sit down. - No.
丹妮  拜托
Dani, please.
坐下好吗
Please sit down.
丹妮
Dani.
我邀请我的朋友们来
I invited my friends
是因为这是千载难逢的体验
because this is a once-in-a-lifetime thing,
我想和你们分享
and I wanted to share it.
特别是我知道我的朋友里有人能够领会
Especially with my friends who I knew would appreciate it.
因为我
Because I...
-我为这里感到骄傲  -好吧
- I am proud of this place. - Okay.
好吧  但我不是人类学家
Okay, but I'm not an anthropologist
我一点也不理解这些
and I don't understand any of this.
-是是是  我知道  -我搞不懂
- Yes, yes, yes. I know. - I don't get it.
我知道  但是
I know. And, and yet,
你能来我是最激动的
I was the most excited for you to come.
来  闻下这个
Here. Here, smell this.
这是什么
What is it?
-能让你冷静下来  -不  我没事
- It calms you down. - No, I'm fine.
我不想闻
I don't want it.
-你确定吗  -不用
- Are you sure? - No...
我真的想走  佩尔  我不  我不想闻
I really want to go, Pelle. I don't... I don't want it.
好吧
Okay.
我明白你现在的感受  丹妮
I know what you're going through, Dani.
我现在的感受
What am I going through?
因为我也失去了父母
Because I lost my parents, too.
-什么  不不  佩尔  -是是
- What? No, no, Pelle. - Yes, yes, yes...
我不是在说这个
That is not what I'm talking about.
-我知道你不是在说这个  -我不是在说我的家人
- I know that's not what you're talking about. - I'm not talking about my family.
-我很小的时候父母就去世了  -我不是在说我的家人
- I lost my parents when I was a little boy. - I'm not talking about my family...
他们在火中丧生
They burned up in a fire.
不  我不是在说这个
No, I wasn't talking about that.
我的父母  在火中丧生
My parents, they burned up in a fire
严格来说  我就成了孤儿
and I became, technically, an orphan.
所以请相信我理解你的感受
So believe me when I tell you that I know what it's like.
因为我真的懂  我懂  我懂
Because I do, I really, really do.
不过我和你的不同在于我从未体会过迷茫
Yet my difference is, I never got the chance to feel lost,
因为我在这里有个家
because I had a family here.
大家都接纳我  拥抱我
Where everyone embraced me. And swept me up.
养大我的这个社群
And I was raised by a community
不会计较输赢得失
that doesn't bicker over what's theirs and what's not theirs.
和你的社群不同
That's what you were given.
我一直都有坚强的后盾
But I have always felt held.
有一个家  一个真正的家
By a family. A real family.
每个人都值得拥有
Which everyone deserves.
你也值得
And you deserve.
佩尔  克里斯蒂安可能会进来
Pelle, Christian could walk in.
我说的就是他
He's what I'm talking about.
他是个好朋友  我喜欢他  但是
He's my good friend and I like him, but...
丹妮  你觉得他是你的后盾吗
Dani, do you feel held by him?
他有给你家的感觉吗
Does he feel like home to you?
你怎么样
How you doing?
今天不好过
Today was tough.
你不会有事吧
You gonna be okay?
刚刚看到的事你没觉得不安吗
Are you not disturbed by what we just saw?
我当然觉得不安
Yeah, of course I am.
太令人震惊了
That was really, really shocking.
不过我想保持开放的心态
I'm trying to keep an open mind though.
这是一种文化  明白吗
That's cultural, you know?
我们把老人塞进养老院
We stick our elders in nursing homes.
他们肯定觉得那才是令人不安
I'm sure they find that disturbing.
你们好
Hello.
你们想来参加我们的特殊仪式吗
Would you like to be joining us with a special ceremony?
怎么了  什么仪式
Why? What's happening now?
女神大人  怀着感激及赞颂  我们向您献上这份薄礼
不好
你们有没有听到那咕噜声
我想她还没吃饱
我没听到咕噜声
你们有听到吗
好吧  可能是我的肚子在咕噜
但是
万一冒犯到仁慈的母亲就不好了
说得对
但是我们已经献上了最漂亮的宝石和最多产的果树
我们还能献上什么
你们可献上我
你  小布鲁尔
想把自己的生命献给我们敬爱的女神
如果她接受的话
你真勇敢  小布鲁尔
勇敢  回到她的怀抱有何勇敢可言
这是干什么
What's happening?
不  等等  住手
No, wait, wait. Stop!
不
停下
放开他  他已经展示了勇气
你能慢点吗  等一下  宝贝
Okay, can you slow down? Just wait a sec, babe.
拜托  克里斯蒂安  这真的很不对劲
Please, Christian, this is feeling really wrong.
我们得走了
We need to leave.
我知道这很奇怪
I know that this is weird,
-因为这是异国文化  -不
- but it's because it's alien. - No...
-我们没接触过这种文化  -不  克里斯蒂安
- We haven't been exposed to anything like this. - No, Christian.
拜托  这里简直还未开化  我们得走了
No, please. This is completely backwards. We need to leave.
-我们只是需要适应  -我不想适应  我想走
- We just need to acclimate. - I don't want to acclimate. I want to go.
我不能走  对不起  没得商量
Well, I can't. I'm sorry. Period.
我的论文要写这里
I'm doing my thesis on this.
什么  什么时候的事
What? Since when
我今天决定的
Since I decided today.
你知道选课题这事让我有多煎熬
You know how much of a nightmare this has been for me to figure out.
我还犯了个错  把这事告诉乔希了
And I've made the mistake of telling Josh,
现在他要跟我竞争
and now he's competing with me.
他想写就让他写吧  我们得走了
So if he wants it, let him have it. We need to leave.
你看不清这里的情况吗
Can you not see what's going on here?
这种级别的传统
This level of tradition?
没人见过  没人发表过
No one's seen this. No one's written anything on it.
而他们邀请我们来参与
And they've invited us to be a part of it.
-他们为什么邀请我们  -你不明白这有多难得吗
- Why have they invited us? - Can't you see what a privilege that is?
-因为佩尔邀请了  -佩尔为什么邀请
- Because Pelle did. - Why did Pelle?
-因为他信任我们  -他们为什么要信任我们
- Because he trusts us. - Why would they trust us?
你们是一帮投机取巧的人类学学生
You're opportunistic anthropology students.
也许正是因为我们是人类学学生
Maybe because we're anthropology students.
-天呐  -也许他们想要
- Oh, my God. - Maybe they want
-你是睁眼瞎吗  -找个人记录这一切
- Are you fucking blind? - someone to document this.
他们举行的是异教仪式  有人从悬崖上跳下来
They're doing pagan rituals. People are jumping off cliffs.
他们的存续全靠永远不让外人知道
They depend on no one knowing about this ever.
不一定
Not necessarily.
好吧  我想走
Okay. I want to leave.
好吧  那你可以走  但我要留下
Okay, then you can leave. But I'm staying.
我邀请了你  这我不后悔  但我是有目的而来的
I invited you, and I don't regret that, but I'm here for a reason.
你是不是不爱我了
Do you not love me anymore?
那和这有什么关系
What does that have to do with this?
我们处于贬值阶段
We're in the devaluation phase.
已经很长时间了  下一步就是丢弃
We've been in it for a long time, and next comes discard.
别用你心理学课本上那一套来分析我们的关系好吗
Can we spare our relationship your textbook psychology keywords?
我们已经这样很长时间了
We've been in this for a while.
你试图抽身  我不肯面对
You've been trying to pull away, and I've been in denial.
你可得好好夸夸自己  宝贝
Please. Give yourself some credit, babe.
看来你已经弄得明明白白了
Looks like you've got this all figured out.
什么
What?
转念一想  有件事我不吐不快
Actually, you know what? I'm gonna say one thing.
你随意地送我一束现摘的花束
When you casually gift me an impromptu bouquet of flowers,
-只会让我想到  -什么花
- that just makes me think... - What flowers?
我该怎么还这份情
how and when am I supposed to pay that back?
你给我的一切都是在提醒我
Everything you give me is a reminder
在这段关系中  我为你做的还不够
that I'm not doing enough for you in this relationship.
你是说午餐的时候
What, at lunch?
我那是一时兴起
I picked those on a whim!
别跟我说你不是另有目的
Don't try to tell me that you had no ulterior motive.
-我能有什么目的  -你过生日
- Yeah! What motives do I have? - On your birthday?
我什么都没送你
The day after I didn't get you something?
你是认真的吗
Are you being serious?
行吧
Okay, fine.
又要扮演受害者了
Play the wounded party again.
你是个自我否定的利他主义者  我是个偏执的混蛋
You're just a self-denying altruist, and I'm a paranoid dick.
你心中没有一丝一毫的算计
You don't have a conniving bone in your body.
-你觉得我在算计什么  -你就是在算计  丹妮
- What is it you imagine I'm conniving? - You are, Dani!
你每次"一时兴起"  都让我觉得亏欠你了
I feel locked into your debt every time you do something "just because."
-我没觉得你亏欠我  -因为不存在"一时兴起"
- I don't keep you in my debt! - Because it's never "just because."
我只是想对你好
I was being kind.
行吧  我是混蛋
Okay, fine. I'm the asshole.
-谁都不是混蛋  -显然我是
- Nobody's the asshole. - I clearly am.
你无私地送我花  我还觉得被套牢了  操
You selflessly gave me flowers, and I feel trapped. Fuck!
你不是要走吧
Are you actually gonna leave?
-我还有正事要干  -你就这么扔下我吗
- I'm supposed to be working here. - You're gonna leave me like this?
克里斯蒂安
Christian!
你有没有...不好意思
Do you... Sorry.
你有没有安眠药能给我
Do you have a sleeping pill I can take?
有  好的
Yeah, sure.
谢了
Thanks.
你会吵醒她的
You're gonna wake her.
佩尔
Pelle.
你在做什么
What'cha doin'?
打理下花园
Just working in the garden.
伙计
Hey, man.
有消息了吗
Any word?
他们说你可以写
Yeah, they said you can do it.
只要你不提及任何名字
As long as you absolutely don't use any names.
-好的  -也不能暗示任何地点
- Okay. - Or the location is never even hinted at.
-好的  -还有你必须签一份保证书
- Okay. - And you'll have to sign an agreement to that.
而且你要和克里斯蒂安平分
And you're splitting it with Christian
因为是他先找我的
because he came to me first.
这...我们会想办法的
Well, that's... We'll... We'll figure that out.
我要去方便一下
I gotta go take a leak.
我能问你个事吗
Here, can I ask you something?
说
Yeah.
你知道这是什么吗
Do you know what this is?
我在克里斯蒂安的床下找到的
I found it under Christian's bed.
这是爱情卢恩  施展爱情魔咒的
That's a love rune. Casts a love spell.
-爱情卢恩  -嗯
- A love rune. - Yeah.
-在克里斯蒂安床下  -是的
- Under Christian's bed? - Yeah, yeah.
怎么样了
What's going on?
长老说你可以写论文
The elders said you can do your thesis
只要别提及真实的名字或地点
as long as you don't use the actual names or location.
真的吗
Are you serious?
真的
Yeah.
天呐  谢谢你
Oh, my God, thank you, man.
真是天大的好消息  谢谢你
That is incredible news. Thank you.
你要和乔希平分
You're splitting it with Josh as well.
我已经跟他说了我完全不介意
Yeah, I already told him I'm totally fine with that.
好吧
Okay.
我觉得我妹妹
Well, I think my sister
玛雅喜欢上你了
Maja has taken a liking to you.
是吗
Yeah?
红头发那个
The red head?
事实上  她去年刚到默许年龄
Actually, she just got the byxmyndig last year.
基本上就是说  到了...
It basically means that, uh, you are...
到了可以做爱的年纪  脱裤许可年龄
You are allowed to have sex. Pants license.
好吧  那很好
Okay. Good for her.
不  不不不  你在干什么  快离开那里
你在干什么  你个蠢货  滚开
把你恶心的老二收起来
什么  好吧  冷静  冷静
What? Okay, relax. Relax!
我做什么了
What did I do?
这是我们的祖先  你在亵渎我的族人
-佩尔  怎么回事  -怎么了  怎么了
- Pelle, what is going on? - What happened? What happened?
你的傻逼美国朋友  他亵渎了颠倒树
我做什么了  我做什么了
What did I do? What did I do?
老兄  行了
Dude! Okay!
你没看到他干了什么吗
你亵渎了祖先树
You pissed on the ancestral tree.
-这棵树  那又怎样  -是的  是的
- The tree... So what? - Yes, yes.
"那又怎样"
"So what?"
你没听见他说了什么吗
-我不知道  -不  这...
- I didn't know. - No, it's...
那棵树连结着我们所有的逝者
That tree is tied to all of our dead.
那只是一桩枯木
It's a dead tree, though.
-枯死了  -我知道
- It's dead. - Yeah, yeah, I know.
但它对我们很重要
But it's important to us.
我尿急  我又不知道这是特别的树
I just had to pee. I didn't know it was special.
我明白
No, I know.
我明白你不知道  但是...
We know that you didn't know that, but it's just...
我怎么会知道
Well, how was I supposed to know...
你不会在墓碑上撒尿吧
You wouldn't pee on a gravestone, right?
显然不会  但是...
Obviously not, but...
操  这...
Fuck! I mean...
你对他做了什么
What did you do to him?
我都不知道我在为什么道歉  我要道歉吗
I don't know what I'm apologizing for... Do I apologize?
之后再道歉
Apologize later.
-好了  -靠  你好
- Okay. - Oh, shit. Hi.
告诉他没关系  他不知道
好的
Okay.
-好的  -什么鬼
- Okay. - What the fuck!
我去跟乌尔夫老爹谈
她说了什么
What did she say?
她说不会有事的
She said it's gonna be okay,
她会跟乌尔夫谈  为这个错误道歉
and she'll talk to Ulf and apologize for the mistake.
真的吗  她还说了什么
Seriously? What else did she say?
你睡得好吗
You get some good sleep?
那就好
Good.
那边出什么事了
What happened over there?
马克...他...
Mark's... just...
昨晚的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about last night.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
我不想跟你吵架  克里斯蒂安
I don't want us to be fighting, Christian.
好吧
Well...
我也不想
Me neither.
真的很高兴认识你
It was really nice to meet you.
很抱歉  我们要走了
I'm so sorry. We're actually leaving.
什么
What?
-嗯  -康妮
- Yeah. - Connie.
西蒙跟一个村民去开卡车了
Simon is getting the truck with one of them now.
-康妮  -没出什么事吧
- Connie. - Is everything okay?
康妮
Connie.
找到你了
Oh, there.
西蒙  他要我告诉你
Simon, he told me to tell you
扬开车送他去火车站了
that, uh, Jan drove him to the train station.
送完西蒙后
And after, uh, Simon gets dropped off,
他再回来送你
he's sending the truck back for you.
什么
What?
你去火车站和他汇合
You will meet him, uh, there.
不
No.
他为什么不等我一起走
Why would he just go without me?
他不会那么做的
He... He wouldn't do that.
车里只能坐下两个人
Well, the truck only had room for two.
所以
So...
什么意思
What does that mean?
这根本说不通
That doesn't even make any sense.
他会跟我说一声的
He would have told me.
今天唯一一趟火车90分钟后就要发车了
Today's only train leaves in 90 minutes.
往返火车站大约需要35分钟
It takes about 35 minutes to go there and back.
所以他们不想浪费时间
So they didn't want to waste time.
我可以坐在他腿上
So I could have sat on his lap.
嗯  我也觉得可以
Yes, I imagined that, too,
但是  我们不能违反交通法规
but, you know, we... We don't break traffic laws.
好吗
Okay?
他们就这么走了  丢下我一个人
So they've just gone. They've left me just now.
康妮  车里坐不下
Now, Connie. There was no room in the truck.
再说了  车会回来接你的
Yet, it is coming right back for you. Yeah.
太扯了
This is bullshit.
马上就要吃午饭了
Okay, lunch in a bit.
这里是怎么分配工作或职位的
And how are jobs or roles assigned?
根据我们小时候表现出来的特征
That's based on traits we show as kids.
例如  他分配到的是保护
For example, he was assigned to protect.
所以他的朝圣之旅是去当医生
So he made his pilgrimage as doctor.
他没事吧
Is he gonna be okay?
你看他
I mean...
嗯  他是个很敏感的人
Yeah, he's a very sensitive guy.
这周对他来说很重要
It's a big week for him.
抱歉
Sorry.
西蒙扔下康妮自己走了
Simon left without Connie.
-天呐  真的吗  -嗯
- Jesus, really? - Yeah.
太混蛋了
What a dick move.
-她还好吗  -不好
- Is she okay? - Uh, no.
-她刚知道  -她有说原因吗
- She just got told. - Did she say why?
没有
No, no.
真糟心
That sucks.
其实我还想问问男女关系方面
On the... On the subject of couples actually, um...
这里有乱伦的问题吗
Is there ever an issue here with incest?
抱歉  你也知道  这么小的社群
Sorry, I mean, you know, small communities.
我们的血统传承得非常好
Well, the bloodlines are very well-preserved.
所以结合必须获得长老的认可
So, uh, the elders must approve mates.
有时表亲也会结合
Cousins can sometimes mate.
但我们尊重他们对近亲婚配的禁忌
But we do respect their incest taboo.
所以我们经常需要邀请外来者
So we often need to invite outside people.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你愿意来帮忙吗
Would you like to help join us?
-好啊  -来吧
- Sure, yeah. - Come.
你知不知道
Do you... Do you know, um...
你见过西蒙吗
Have you seen Simon anywhere?
见过  有人送他去火车站了
Yes. He was driven to the station.
你没有跟他告别吗
Did you not say goodbye?
没  我没有
No. No, I didn't.
不过不要紧  没事
But, uh, that's okay, that's okay.
这是在做什么
What are we making here?
肉饼
Meat tarts!
谢谢
Thank you.
她说你真漂亮
She said you're so beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
她也很漂亮
She's so beautiful.
我们称之为情感乐谱
We describe it like emotional sheet music.
上面写了什么
What does it say?
每个卢恩字母
Well, each runic letter
都代表十六个影响中的一个
stands for one of the 16 affects,
从最神圣到最邪恶
which are graded from most holy to most unholy.
举个例子  这个代表悲伤
This one, for example, is about grief.
你可以看到最后
You can see at the end, however,
都是空白页
we have blank pages.
这是因为《鲁比拉达》是一本不断在更新的著作
This is because the Rubi Radr is a work forever in progress.
永远在进化
Forever evolving.
我们有成百上千本这样的书
We have many, many hundreds of these.
谁来决定书的补充内容呢
And who decides what gets added?
这个版本是由鲁宾撰写的
Well, uh, this iteration is being written by Rubin.
那个残疾人吗
The disabled?
从出生起
Since birth.
他画  我们长老翻译
He draws and we, the elders, interpret.
你看  乔希
You see, Josh,
鲁宾不受普通认知的干扰
Rubin is unclouded by normal cognition.
这令他的心能包罗万象
It makes him open for the source.
鲁宾死后会怎样
What happens when Rubin dies?
你们就干等着下一个
Do you just wait for a baby that is...
不受干扰的孩子降生吗
not clouded?
不  不  不
No, no, no.
鲁宾是近亲结合的后代
Rubin was a product of inbreeding.
我们所有先知
All of our Oracles
都是有意的近亲结合的后代
are deliberate products of inbreeding.
我能拍张照片吗
Can I take a photograph?
什么
What?
拍张照片
A photograph?
-不行  绝对不行  -好的  抱歉
- No. Absolutely not. - Okay, sorry.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
操  是她
Fuck, yep, that's her.
真好  她走了
Great. She's walking away.
晚饭准备好了
该吃晚饭了
谢谢
Thank you.
Thanks.
谢谢
Tack.
Thanks.
有人见到康妮了吗
Has anyone seen Connie?
马克之前好像见过她
I think Mark saw her earlier.
之前我看到她跑得像是
I'm sure I saw her trying out
参加奥运会选拔赛
for the sprinting Olympics earlier.
什么  在哪
What? Where?
抱歉打断  我知道发生了什么
Sorry, but I can say what happened.
她男友用火车站的座机
Her boyfriend called the landline
打来电话  让康妮冷静下来了
from the train station and calmed Connie down.
然后她向我们道歉  我送她去和他汇合了
Then she begged our pardon and I drove her to meet him.
好的  这样我就放心了
Okay, well, that's a relief.
为什么西蒙要扔下她自己走
Why would Simon leave without her?
肯定只是沟通出现了误会
I'm sure it was just a miscommunication.
我看得出你可能也会这么做
I could see you possibly doing that.
你这话什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
没什么
Never mind.
有人还在为他们的祖先树耿耿于怀
Someone's still sore about their ancestral tree.
老兄  他会杀了我吗
Dude, is he going to kill me?
你了解到关于《鲁比拉达》的事了吗
Did you learn anything about the Rubi Radr?
怎么  你又想合作了
So now you wanna collaborate?
谢谢你了
Okay, thank you.
-我知道有个长老  -谢谢
- I know that one elder... - Thank you.
让你看了一眼
gave you a glimpse of it.
谢谢  我不该提起的
Thank you. Sorry I brought it up.
天啊  老兄  搞什么
Oh, my God, dude. What the fuck?
-那是...  -那是什么
- Is that... - What is that?
那是阴毛吗
Is that a fucking pube?
只是根头发
It's just a hair.
是阴部的头发吧
Yeah, a pubic hair.
老兄  冷静
Dude, calm down.
你有什么好尴尬的
Why are you embarrassed?
有毛的饼又不是你发的
You're not the one giving out hair pies.
卢恩字母组合
情感乐谱
老天  他还在盯着我看
Jesus Christ. He's still fucking lookin' at me.
你能跟我来吗
You'll come with me?
-什么  -来吗
- What? - You'll come?
我带你看
I'll show you.
好  行
Okay, sure.
-好吗  -行  好
- Yeah? - Yeah, great.
我待会回来  她好像要带我看
I'll be back. I guess she's gonna show me.
能再给我一片安眠药吗
Can I borrow another sleeping pill?
-好  没问题  -谢了
- Yeah, sure, yeah. - Thanks.
谢谢
Thank you.
搞什么  马克
What the fuck, Mark?
你在搞什么鬼  关上门
What the fuck are you doing? Close the door,
我们不该进这里的
we're not supposed to be in here.
你说马克还和那个女孩在一起吗
Do you think Mark's still up with that girl?
没什么好惊讶的
I wouldn't be surprised.
不过乔希呢
What about Josh though?
我真的不太关心
I'm honestly not too concerned.
我们
We...
有一件遗憾的事要宣布
have something regretful to announce.
今天早上我们发现
This morning the 19th Book of Rubi Radr
第十九卷《鲁比拉达》从神庙失踪了
was found missing from the Temple.
我们不想指责谁
We don't want to point fingers,
不过我们恳请拿走它的人
yet, we kindly ask that whoever took it
把它放回原处
to return it to its original place.
你可以把它放回神庙
You can leave it in the Temple,
那里不会有人看守
which will be left unguarded, unwatched.
不会有人知道是你拿走的
Nobody needs to know it was you.
你们的朋友乔希在哪
Where is your friend, Josh?
他不见了  我们不知道他在哪
I know. We have no idea.
他和你们的另一位朋友
He and your other friend,
他们都在同一天消失了
they both disappears the same day.
-这情况你们明白吧  -是的  很显然
- You see how it looks? - Yes, obviously.
但我对你们发誓我们完全不知情
But I swear to you we're in the dark on this.
我们和你们一样疑惑
We're just as confused as you are.
我们确实看到马克昨晚和那个女孩走了
We did see Mark go off with that girl last night.
-哪个女孩  -英格
- What girl? - Inge.
是的  但马克不会做这种事
Yeah, but Mark wouldn't have done this.
不过乔希
Josh on the other hand,
他和我们一起上床睡觉
he came to bed with us
我们醒来时他就不见了
and when we woke up, he was gone.
如果真是他拿的  我恳求你们理解
And if he did take that book, I just pray you understand
我们不算他的朋友
we don't associate as friends of his
也不是合作者之类的
or collaborators or anything.
以任何方式或形式与此事有任何联系
We would just be so embarrassed to be connected to this
我们都会很难堪
in any way, shape or form.
希望书会被归还
Let's hope it gets returned.
我也希望
I hope so too.
我感觉有责任
I feel responsible.
你和奥德可以去找他们
Well, you and Odd, you can go looking for them.
-好的  -或许你能弥补
- Yes. - Maybe you can redeem this.
你和女人们去进行今天的活动
You are going with the women for the day's activity.
希芙要你去她家见她
And Siv wants to see you in her house.
你没问题吧
You okay?
好  好的
Okay. Okay.
这是重头戏
This is the big one.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
直视她的双眼
Look into her eyes.
我能问问这到底是什么吗
Can I ask what this is exactly?
这是...比赛专用的茶
It's... tea for the competition.
然后你把杯子放这里
And then you, glass here.
然后我们喝掉
And then we drink it.
-好吗  -好的
- Okay? - Okay.
好的
Okay.
-天呐  -开始了
- Oh, God. - Here we go!
很久以前  在这里
黑暗之君将哈加的年轻人引至草地  诱惑他们跳舞
他们一旦起舞就停不下来  直至死亡
现在  我们对黑暗之君发起生命的挑战  舞到摔倒为止
坚持到最后的人将因其耐力而被加冕
请进
Please. Come in.
首先我要说
First thing I just have to say,
我不知道乔希在哪
I have no idea where Josh is.
我以我母亲的性命发誓
And I can swear to that on my mother's life.
你觉得玛雅怎么样
How do you feel about Maja?
玛雅
About Maja?
我觉得她怎么样  什么意思
How do I feel about her how?
长老们认可你和她结合
You have been approved to mate with her.
占星显示你是良配
You're an ideal astrological match.
她对你寄予厚望
And she has fixed her hopes on you.
我不太明白你的意思
I'm not sure I understand what you mean.
我都没跟她说过话
I haven't even spoken to her.
你来之前她就相中你了
She fixed on you before you came.
佩尔给她看了一张照片
Pelle showed her a photo.
我是和女友一起来的
I'm here with someone.
丹妮是我女友
I'm here with Dani.
丹妮不会知道的
Dani will not know.
我不是想让你们结婚
I am not proposing marriage.
你不会获得认可的
You wouldn't be approved for that.
那你问的是什么意思
Okay, so what is it you're asking?
我是问你是否愿意和玛雅结合
I'm asking if you care to mate with Maja.
仅限一夜
It's a one-night offer.
我好像吃了她的一根阴毛
I think I ate one of her pubic hairs.
听起来没什么问题
Sounds probably right.
从学术的角度来看
From an academic perspective...
这也能提供了解我们的性仪式的独特视角
It would also provide a unique glimpse into our sexual rites.
我不参与就不能获得独特视角吗
Can I not have a unique glimpse without participating?
停
Stop!
待在这里
Stay here.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
-我们在做什么  -你会明白的
- What are we doing? - You'll see.
停
Stop!
-你太棒了  -什么意思
- You're so good! - What does that mean?
八强  八强
Eight! Eight!
-我们是八强  -什么
- We're now eight left! - What?
克里斯蒂安
Christian?
给你的
For you.
谢谢
Thanks.
这是什么
What is it?
这是...抱歉
It's... Sorry.
有特殊效果的泉水
Spring water with special properties.
好吧
Okay.
-好的  -有什么作用
- Okay. - What does it do?
它...能让你卸下防备
It... it breaks down your defenses
使你容易接受影响
and opens you for the influence.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Thanks.
不客气
You're welcome.
我又想了一下
You know what?
我担心会有不好的体验
I'm worried I'll have a bad trip.
不不  不会的  相信我
No, no. You won't. You won't. Trust me.
停
反向
开始
停
-我不会说瑞典语  -什么
- I don't speak Swedish. - What?
你想说瑞典语吗
我想说吗
你想说
我们在对话
我能听懂
我们互相理解
我们不需要用语言交流  舞蹈就够了
什么  什么
What? What?
什么情况
What's happening?
你是我们的五月女王
You are our May Queen.
-我吗  -是的
- Me? - Yes!
-为什么  -你赢了
- Why? - You won!
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
什么  天啊
What? Oh, my god.
妈  妈
Mom? Mom?
天呐  丹妮  五月女王
Oh, my God, Dani! May Queen!
吃鲱鱼吗
Herring?
为什么
What for?
这是传统  为了好运
It's tradition. For good luck.
是的
Yeah.
-什么  -你必须整个吞下去
- What? - And you must eat it whole.
-但是先吃鱼尾  -不不不
- But the tails go in first. - No, no, no!
你必须试试
You must try!
很棒的尝试
Very good try.
打扰一下
Excuse me...
这是什么情况
What's going on?
你为什么要这么做
Why did you do that?
敬我们的五月女王
To our May Queen!
欢迎  干杯
Välkommen! Skål!
干杯
Skål!
你现在是我们的家人了  对吗
You are in the family now. Yes?
没错  你是我们的家人了
Yes, you are in the family.
就像姐妹
Like sisters.
现在  按照传统  五月女王该去
Now, it's traditional for the May Queen
祝福我们的庄稼和牲畜了
to bless our crops and livestock.
看到你刚刚从咸鲱鱼继承的运气后
And after the luck you just inherited from that salt herring,
我们都应该受到双倍鼓舞
we should all be doubly encouraged.
克里斯蒂安能和我一起吗
Can Christian come with me?
不能
Nay.
女王必须独自乘坐
The Queen must ride alone.
跟我唱
Repeat after me.
吸气
Breathe in.
为你提升精力
For your vitality.
我们现在该去希芙家了
We shall go now to Siv's house.
这是做什么
What's this?
这是只有女王能参加的特殊会面
It is a special meeting, only for the Queens.
她会祝福你
And she will bless you.
那是做什么
What's that?
那不是我们该做的
That's not for us.
我觉得你不该去
I think you should not.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
不  别停
射进来
我能感觉到
感觉到孩子了
克里斯蒂安
Christian?
Christian.
你好  你醒了啊
Hello, there you are.
听好了
Listen.
你不能说话  也不能动
You can't speak. You can't move.
明白吗
All right?
很好
Good.
在今天互惠神明的这个日子
On this, the day of our deity of reciprocity,
我们聚在一起向我们珍贵的太阳
we gather to give special thanks
致以特别感谢
to our treasured sun.
作为对我们父亲的献祭
As an offering to our father,
我们今天将交出九条人命
we will today surrender nine human lives.
哈加索取  同时也付出
As Harga takes, so Harga also gives.
因此  对每一位献祭的新成员
Thus, for every new blood sacrificed,
我们将献上一位我们的人
we will dedicate one of our own.
也就是四位新成员
That is four new bloods.
四位哈加人
Four from Harga.
还有一位将被女王选出
And one to be chosen by the Queen.
一共九位将死亡
Nine in all to die
并在伟大的循环中获得新生
and be reborn in the great cycle.
四位新成员已被奉上
The four new bloods have already been supplied.
至于我们的人  已经有两位献身
As for our end, we have two already dedicated
还有两位自告奋勇
and two who have volunteered.
英格马和乌尔夫
Ingemar and Ulf.
你们从外界带来了祭品
You have brought outside offerings.
还自愿奉上自身
Plus volunteering your own bodies.
你们今天将与一切共达和谐
You will today be joined in harmony with everything.
还有佩尔  带来了新成员
And to Pelle, who has brought new blood
还有新的五月女王
and our new May Queen,
今天你将因你不受干扰的直觉获得嘉奖
you will today be honored for your unclouded intuition.
至于我们的第九个祭品
And so, for our ninth offering,
按照传统  我们美丽的女王将在
it is traditional that our fair Queen shall choose
预选的新成员
between a preselected new blood
和命定的哈加人中做出选择
and a specially-ordained Hargan.
托比昂
Torbjorn.
光荣的托比昂  请上前来
Honorable Torbjorn, please step forward.
以及
And...
克里斯蒂安·休斯
Christian Hughes.
这就是第九个也是最后一个祭品的候选人
These are the candidates for the ninth and final offering.
我们耐心等待你的裁定
We patiently await your verdict.
过来
好了孩子们
切除内脏的时候  一定要小心不能戳破
小心一点
你握住这里
像这样  沿着边切
强大而可怕的野兽
通过你  我们净化自身最邪恶的影响
现在我们将你驱逐至深处  让你反省自身的邪恶
从紫杉树上采的  消除痛苦
从紫杉树上采的  消除恐惧
仲夏夜惊魂